I'd like to try something new.
أود تجربة شيء جديد.
Those of you who are able,
القادرين منكم،
please stand up.
أرجو منهم الوقوف.
OK, so I'm going to name some names.
حسنًا، سأعرض عليكم بعض الأسماء.
When you hear a name that you don't recognize,
وعندما تسمعون اسمًا لا تعرفونه،
you can't tell me anything about them,
ولا تستطيعون إخباري أي شيء عنه،
I'd like you to take a seat
أود منكم الجلوس
and stay seated.
والبقاء مكانكم.
The last person standing, we're going to see what they know. OK?
وآخر شخص يبقى واقفًا، سوف يُطلعنا على ما يعرفه. حسنًا؟
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
All right.
حسنًا.
Eric Garner.
(إريك غارنر).
Mike Brown.
(مايك براون).
Tamir Rice.
(تامير رايس).
Freddie Gray.
(فرادي غراي).
So those of you who are still standing,
الأشخاص الذين لا زالوا واقفين،
I'd like you to turn around and take a look.
أود منكم أن تلتفتوا حولكم وتلقوا نظرة.
I'd say half to most of the people are still standing.
أظن أن نصف الحاضرين ما زالوا واقفين.
So let's continue.
لذا دعونا نُكمل.
Michelle Cusseaux.
(ميشال كيسوو).
Tanisha Anderson.
(تنيشا أندرسون).
Aura Rosser.
(أورا روزار).
Meagan Hockaday.
(ميغان هوكاداي).
So if we look around again,
إذا ألقينا نظرة مجددًا،
there are about four people still standing,
فقد بقي حوالي 4 أشخاص فقط واقفين،
and actually I'm not going to put you on the spot.
ولكني في الحقيقة لا أنوي أن أحرجكم.
I just say that to encourage transparency, so you can be seated.
قلت ذلك فقط لتشجيع الشفافية، لذلك يمكنكم الجلوس.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
So those of you who recognized the first group of names know
الذين تعرفوا على المجموعة الأولى من الأسماء يعرفون
that these were African-Americans who have been killed by the police
أن هؤلاء أمريكيون من أصول إفريقية قتلوا على يد الشرطة
over the last two and a half years.
على مر العامين والنصف الماضيين.
What you may not know
وربما لا تعرفون
is that the other list is also African-Americans
أن القائمة الأخرى تضم أيضًا أمريكيين من أصول أفريقية
who have been killed within the last two years.
قُتلوا خلال السنتين الماضيين.
Only one thing distinguishes the names that you know
يُوجد شيء واحد فقط يُميز بين الأسماء التي تعرفونها
from the names that you don't know:
والأسماء التي لا تعرفونها:
gender.
النوع الاجتماعي.
So let me first let you know that there's nothing at all distinct
أولًا دعوني أوضح لكم أنه لا يوجد أي شيء مميز مطلقًا
about this audience
بشأن هذا الجمهور
that explains the pattern of recognition that we've just seen.
فيما يتعلق بنمط التعرف كما رأيناه.
I've done this exercise dozens of times around the country.
قُمت بهذه التجربة العديد من المرات في أنحاء الدولة.
I've done it to women's rights organizations.
قُمت بذلك مع منظمات حقوق المرأة.
I've done it with civil rights groups.
قُمت بذلك مع مجموعات الحقوق المدنية.
I've done it with professors. I've done it with students.
قُمت بذلك مع الأساتذة. قُمت بذلك مع الطلاب.
I've done it with psychologists. I've done it with sociologists.
قُمت بذلك مع علماء النفس. قُمت بذلك مع علماء الاجتماع.
I've done it even with progressive members of Congress.
حتى أنني قُمت بذلك مع أعضاء الكونغرس التقدميين.
And everywhere, the awareness of the level of police violence
وفي كل مكان، الوعي بمستوى العنف الذي يقوم به رجال الشرطة
that black women experience
الذي تمر به النساء السود
is exceedingly low.
مُنخفض جدًا.
Now, it is surprising, isn't it, that this would be the case.
والآن، إنه لمن المفاجئ، أليس كذلك، بأن هذه ستكون القضية.
I mean, there are two issues involved here.
أعني بذلك، أنه توجد هنا قضيتان.
There's police violence against African-Americans,
قضية عنف رجال الشرطة تجاه الأمريكيين من أصول إفريقية،
and there's violence against women,
والقضية الأخرى حول العنف ضد النساء،
two issues that have been talked about a lot lately.
تعتبر هاتان القضيتان الأكثر مناقشة مؤخرًا.
But when we think about who is implicated by these problems,
ولكن عندما نُفكر في المتورطين في هذه المشاكل،
when we think about who is victimized by these problems,
ونُفكر في الضحايا المُتضررين من هذه المشاكل،
the names of these black women never come to mind.
أسماء هؤلاء النسوة لا تخطر على البال.
Now, communications experts tell us
الآن، يُخبرنا خبراء التواصل
that when facts do not fit with the available frames,
أنه عندما لا تتلاءم الحقائق مع الأوضاع المتاحة،
people have a difficult time incorporating new facts
فإن الناس يجدون صعوبة في دمج الحقائق الجديدة
into their way of thinking about a problem.
في طريقة تفكيرهم عند وقوع مُشكلة.
These women's names have slipped through our consciousness
أسماء هؤلاء النساء تسللت من خلال وعينا
because there are no frames for us to see them,
لأنه لا يوجد أُطر تُمكننا من رؤيتها،
no frames for us to remember them,
ولا حتى لنتذكرها،
no frames for us to hold them.
ولا للاحتفاظ بها.
As a consequence,
وكنتيجة لذلك،
reporters don't lead with them,
لا يتحاور معهن الصحافيّون،
policymakers don't think about them,
وبالنسبة للسياسيين فلا يعيرونهم اهتمامًا،
and politicians aren't encouraged or demanded that they speak to them.
بالإضافة أنه لا يتم حث السياسيين أو حتى يُطلب منهم التكلم معهم.
Now, you might ask,
الآن، يُمكن أن تتساءل،
why does a frame matter?
لماذا الوضع مهم؟
I mean, after all,
أعني، بعد كل شيء،
an issue that affects black people and an issue that affects women,
القضية التي تؤثر على السود والقضية التي تؤثر على النساء،
wouldn't that necessarily include black people who are women
أليس من الضرورى أن تشمل هذه أشخاصًا سودًا هم نساء
and women who are black people?
ونساءً من السود؟
Well, the simple answer is that this is a trickle-down approach to social justice,
حسنًا، الإجابة ببساطة أن هذا نهج متقدم نحو العدالة الاجتماعية،
and many times it just doesn't work.
وفي كثير من الأحيان يكون غير مُجدٍ.
Without frames that allow us to see
فبدون أُطر تمكننا من رؤية
how social problems impact all the members of a targeted group,
كيف للمشاكل الاجتماعية أن تؤثر فى جميع أفراد المجموعة المستهدفة،
many will fall through the cracks of our movements,
سيسقط الكثيرون خلال الثغرات فى حركاتنا،
left to suffer in virtual isolation.
متروكين ليعانوا من العزلة الافتراضية.
But it doesn't have to be this way.
ولكن ليس بالضرورة أن يكون الأمر بهذه الطريقة.
Many years ago, I began to use the term "intersectionality"
منذ عدة سنوات، بدأت باستعمال مُصطلح "التقاطع المجتمعي"
to deal with the fact that many of our social justice problems
للتعامل مع حقيقة أن العديد من قضايا العدالة الاجتماعية
like racism and sexism
مثل العنصرية والتعصب الجنسي
are often overlapping,
غالبًا ما تكون متداخلة،
creating multiple levels of social injustice.
مما يخلق مستويات متعددة من الظلم الاجتماعي.
Now, the experience that gave rise to intersectionality
الآن، بالنسبة للتجربة التي أدت إلى "التقاطع المجتمعي"
was my chance encounter with a woman named Emma DeGraffenreid.
أتاحت لي فرصة التقابل مع امرأة تُدعى (إيما ديغرافنرايد).
Emma DeGraffenreid was an African-American woman,
(إيما ديغرافنرايد) هي امرأة أمريكية من أصول إفريقية،
a working wife and a mother.
زوجة عاملة وأم.
I actually read about Emma's story from the pages of a legal opinion
في الواقع، لقد قرأت عن قصّة هذه المرأة في صفحات الرأي القانوني
written by a judge who had dismissed Emma's claim
المُحرَّرة من قبل قاضٍ قام برفض شكوى (إيما)
of race and gender discrimination
حول التمييز العنصري والتمييز القائم على النوع الاجتماعي،
Emma, like so many African-American women,
(إيما)، مثل العديد من النساء الأمريكيات من أصول إفريقية،
sought better employment for her family and for others.
تبحث عن عمل أفضل لأسرتها وللآخرين.
She wanted to create a better life for her children and for her family.
فقد أرادت أن تخلق حياة أفضل لأطفالها ولأسرتها.
But she applied for a job,
ولكنها قدمت طلبًا للحصول على عمل،
and she was not hired,
إلا أنه لم يتم توظيفها،
and she believed that she was not hired because she was a black woman.
واعتقدت أنه لم يتم توظيفها لأنها امرأة سوداء.
Now, the judge in question dismissed Emma's suit,
الآن، القاضي المعني بالأمر رفض قضية (إيما)،
and the argument for dismissing the suit was
والحجة التي اعتمدها لرفض دعوتها
that the employer did hire African-Americans
هي أن صاحب العمل قد وظف أمريكيين من أصل إفريقي
and the employer hired women.
وقد وظف أيضًا نساء.
The real problem, though, that the judge was not willing to acknowledge
المشكلة الحقيقية هي أن القاضي لم يكن مستعدًا للاعتراف
was what Emma was actually trying to say,
وهذا ما كانت تحاول (إيما) قوله،
that the African-Americans that were hired,
أن الأمريكيين من أصول إفريقية الذين جرى توظيفهم،
usually for industrial jobs, maintenance jobs, were all men.
للوظائف الصناعية ولوظائف الصيانة، كانوا جميعهم رجالًا.
And the women that were hired,
وبالنسبة للنساء اللواتي تم توظيفهن،
usually for secretarial or front-office work,
عادةً في منصب سكرتيرة او للعمل بمكتب الاستقبال،
were all white.
كن جميعًا ذوات بشرة بيضاء.
Only if the court was able to see how these policies came together
فقط إذا كانت المحكمة قادرة على رؤية كيف اجتمعت هذه السياسات
would he be able to see the double discrimination
سيتمكن القاضي من ملاحظة التمييز المزدوج
that Emma DeGraffenreid was facing.
التي واجهته (إيما ديغرافنرايد).
But the court refused to allow Emma to put two causes of action together
إلا أن المحكمة رفضت أن تسمح (لإيما) بالإدلاء بسببين معًا في نفس الوقت
to tell her story
لكي تروي قصتها
because he believed that, by allowing her to do that,
لأنه يعتقد أنه عند السماح لها بفعل ذلك،
she would be able to have preferential treatment.
فإنها ستكون قادرة على الحصول على معاملة تفضيلية.
She would have an advantage by having two swings at the bat,
ستكون لديها ميزة وجود وسيلتين لكسب القضية،
when African-American men and white women only had one swing at the bat.
بينما الرجال الأمريكيون من أصل إفريقي والنساء البيضاء يمتلكون وسيلة واحدة.
But of course, neither African-American men or white women
ولكن بالطبع لا الرجال الأمريكيون من أصل إفريقي ولا النساء البيضاء
needed to combine a race and gender discrimination claim
يحتاجون للشكوى من التمييز حسب العرق والنوع الاجتماعي
to tell the story of the discrimination they were experiencing.
للتحدث عن التمييز الذي يعانون منه.
Why wasn't the real unfairness
لمَ لمْ يكن الرفض الفعلي الظالم من القانون
law's refusal to protect African-American women
لحماية النساء الأمريكيات من أصل إفريقى
simply because their experiences weren't exactly the same
ببساطة لأن خبرتهن ليست كخبرة
as white women and African-American men?
النساء البيض والرجال الأمريكيين من أصل إفريقي؟
Rather than broadening the frame to include African-American women,
بدلًا من توسيع الإطار ليشمل النساء الأمريكيات الأفارقة،
the court simply tossed their case completely out of court.
المحكمة ببساطة قذفت بقضيتهن خارجها.
Now, as a student of antidiscrimination law,
والآن، بصفتي طالبة في قانون مُكافحة التمييز،
as a feminist,
وكمدافعة عن حقوق المرأة،
as an antiracist,
ومناهضة للعنصرية،
I was struck by this case.
فقد كنت مُندهشة بهذه القضية.
It felt to me like injustice squared.
لقد بدت لى كظلم مضاعف.
So first of all,
لذلك قبل كل شيء،
black women weren't allowed to work at the plant.
لم يكن يُسمح للنساء السود بالعمل في المصنع.
Second of all, the court doubled down on this exclusion
ثانيًا، قامت المحكمة بمضاعفة الإقصاء
by making it legally inconsequential.
بجعله غير منطقى من الناحية القانونية.
And to boot, there was no name for this problem.
وكبداية لذلك، لا يوجد اسم لهذه القضية.
And we all know that, where there's no name for a problem,
وكلنا نعرف، عندما لا تحمل القضية اسمًا،
you can't see a problem,
فإن الرؤية تُحجب عنها،
and when you can't see a problem, you pretty much can't solve it.
وعندما يحدث ذلك، فإنه من الصعب جدًا حلها.
Many years later, I had come to recognize
بعد سنوات عديدة، استوعبت
that the problem that Emma was facing was a framing problem.
أن المشكلة التي كانت تُواجهها (إيما) كانت بوضع المشكلة فى إطار.
The frame that the court was using
الإطار الذي كانت تعتمد عليه المحكمة
to see gender discrimination or to see race discrimination
التمييز بين الجنسين أو التمييز العنصري
was partial, and it was distorting.
كان متحيزًا ومشوّهًا.
For me, the challenge that I faced was
بالنسبة لي، كان التحدي الذي واجهته
trying to figure out whether there was an alternative narrative,
في محاولة معرفة ما إذا كانت هناك رواية بديلة،
a prism that would allow us to see Emma's dilemma,
مؤشر يسمح لنا بالاطلاع على قضية (إيما)،
to rescue her from the cracks in the law,
زاوية مختلفة تسمح لنا بإنقاذها من ثغرات القانون،
that would allow judges to see her story.
ويُمَكن القضاة من رؤية قصتها.
So it occurred to me,
وخطر لي،
maybe a simple analogy to an intersection
ربما قياس بسيط للتشابك
might allow judges to better see Emma's dilemma.
يُمكِّن القضاة من فهم أفضل لقضية (إيما).
So if we think about this intersection, the roads to the intersection would be
إذا كنا نفكر في هذا التشابك، فإن الطرق التي ستؤدي إلى التشابك ستكون
the way that the workforce was structured by race and by gender.
الطريقة التي نُظمت فيها اليد العاملة حسب العرق والنوع الاجتماعي.
And then the traffic in those roads would be the hiring policies
ثم إن السير فى هذه الطرق سيكون بمثابة سياسات التوظيف
and the other practices that ran through those roads.
وغير ذلك من الممارسات التى نهجت هذا النهج.
Now, because Emma was both black and female,
والآن، فيما يتعلق بالأمر كون (إيما) سوداء وامرأة،
she was positioned precisely where those roads overlapped,
فقد وُضعت تحديدًا فى تقاطع هذه الطرق،
experiencing the simultaneous impact
تعانى من التأثير المتزامن
of the company's gender and race traffic.
لانحياز الشركة للنوع الاجتماعي والعرق.
The law -- the law is like that ambulance that shows up
القانون -- يُشبّه بسيارة الإسعاف التي تظهر
and is ready to treat Emma only if it can be shown
ومستعدة لمعالجة إيما
but not where those roads intersected.
ليس عندما يتداخل الإثنين.
So what do you call being impacted by multiple forces
وبالتالى ماذا تسمى الحالة التي تواجه فيها قوى متعددة
and then abandoned to fend for yourself?
وبعدها تترك وحدك للدفاع عن نفسك؟
Intersectionality seemed to do it for me.
بدا لى أن التقاطع المجتمعي فعل ذلك.
I would go on to learn that African-American women,
أريد أن أذهب إلى توضيح أن المرأة الأمريكية الإفريقية،
like other women of color,
مثل أي امرأة ذات لون آخر،
like other socially marginalized people all over the world,
مثل أشخاص المجتمعات الأُخرى المهمشة فى كل أنحاء العالم،
were facing all kinds of dilemmas and challenges
نحن نواجه كل أنواع المعضلات والتحديات
as a consequence of intersectionality,
كنتيجة للتقاطع المجتمعي،
intersections of race and gender,
تقاطع النوع الاجتماعي مع العرق،
of heterosexism, transphobia, xenophobia, ableism,
من كراهية الجنسية المثلية والمتحولين جنسيا ورهاب الأجانب والتمييز ضد المعاقين،
all of these social dynamics come together
كل هذه العوامل المجتمعية تجمعت مع بعضها
and create challenges that are sometimes quite unique.
وأنشأت تحديات فريدة من نوعها فى بعض الأحيان.
But in the same way
ولكن بنفس الطريقة
that intersectionality
التي ينبهنا فيها هذا التقاطع المجتمعي
it also exposes the tragic circumstances
فإنه أيضًا يعرض الظروف المأساوية
under which African-American women die.
التى من خلالها تموت نساء أمريكيات-إفريقيات.
Police violence against black women
عنف الشرطة تجاه النساء ذوات البشرة السوداء
is very real.
حقيقي تمامًا.
The level of violence that black women face
المستوى من العنف التى تواجهه المرأة السوداء
is such that it's not surprising
ليس مفاجئًا
that some of them do not survive their encounters with police.
حيث لم تنجو بعضهن من مواجهات الشرطة.
Black girls as young as seven,
فتيات سود في سن السابعة
great grandmothers as old as 95
وجدات كبيرة في سن الخامسة والتسعين
have been killed by the police.
قتلن على يد الشرطة.
They've been killed in their living rooms,
قتلن فى غرف معيشتهن،
in their bedrooms.
قتلن في غرف نومهن،
They've been killed in their cars.
قتلن فى سياراتهن،
They've been killed on the street.
قتلن فى الشارع،
They've been killed in front of their parents
قتلن أمام آبائهن،
and they've been killed in front of their children.
قتلن أمام أطفالهن.
They have been shot to death.
أُطلق عليهن الرصاص حتي الموت.
They have been stomped to death.
تعرضن للطعن حتى الموت.
They have been suffocated to death.
خُنقن حتي الموت.
They have been manhandled to death.
عُذِّبن حتى الموت.
They have been tasered to death.
صُعقن حتى الموت.
They've been killed when they've called for help.
قُتلن عندما طلبن المساعدة.
They've been killed when they were alone,
قُتلن عندما كنّ وحيدات.
and they've been killed when they were with others.
وقُتلن عندما كن مع آخرين.
They've been killed shopping while black,
قُتلن وهن يتسوقن لأنهن سود،
driving while black,
وأثناء القيادة لأنهن سود،
having a mental disability while black,
لديهن إعاقة ذهنية لأنهن سود،
having a domestic disturbance while black.
لديهن اضطرابات منزلية لأنهن سود،
They've even been killed being homeless while black.
قُتلن حتى وهن مشردات لأنهن سود،
They've been killed talking on the cell phone,
قُتلن وهن يتحدثن فى الهاتف،
laughing with friends,
يضحكن مع أصدقائهن،
sitting in a car reported as stolen
يجلسن فى سيارة أُبلغ بسرقتها
and making a U-turn in front of the White House
ويأخذن المنعطف أمام البيت الأبيض
with an infant strapped in the backseat of the car.
مع رضيع فى المقعد الخلفى للسيارة.
Why don't we know these stories?
لماذا لا نعرف قصصهن؟
Why is it that their lost lives
لماذا فقدان حياتهن
don't generate the same amount of media attention and communal outcry
لا يولد نفس كمية الاهتمام الإعلامي والغضب الشعبي
as the lost lives of their fallen brothers?
كما فقدان حياة إخوانهن المقتولين؟
It's time for a change.
إنه وقت التغيير.
So what can we do?
بالتالى ماذا نستطيع أن نفعل؟
In 2014, the African-American Policy Forum began to demand
فى 2014، المنتدى السياسى الإفريقي-الأمريكي بدأ بإحتجاج
that we "say her name"
لكى "نقول أسماءهن"
at rallies, at protests,
فى مسيرات، فى احتجاجات،
at conferences, at meetings,
فى مؤتمرات، فى اجتماعات،
anywhere and everywhere
فى كل مكان وفى أى وقت
that state violence against black bodies is being discussed.
ليكون العنف ضد الأشخاص ذوى البشرة السوداء موضوعًا على طاولة النقاش.
But saying her name is not enough.
ولكن قول اسمها ليس كافيًا،
We have to be willing to do more.
علينا أن نستعد لبذل المزيد.
We have to be willing to bear witness,
علينا أن نستعد لنكون شاهدين،
to bear witness to the often painful realities
شاهدين على واقع قد يكون مؤلمًا
that we would just rather not confront,
نفضل عدم مواجهته.
the everyday violence and humiliation that many black women have had to face,
العنف والاضطهاد الذى كان على المرأة السوداء أن تواجهه كل يوم،
black women across color,
بسبب اللون،
age, gender expression,
السن ومصطلح النوع الاجتماعي،
sexuality and ability.
الجنس والأهلية.
So we have the opportunity right now --
لذا لدينا الفرصة الآن --
bearing in mind that some of the images that I'm about to share with you
نستحضر فى عقولنا بعض الصور التى أنا على وشك مشاركتها معكم،
may be triggering for some --
ربما تثير بعضكم،
to collectively bear witness to some of this violence.
لنكون جميعًا شاهدين على بعض هذا العنف.
We're going to hear the voice of the phenomenal Abby Dobson.
سوف نستمع لصوت الرائعة (آبي دوبسون).
And as we sit with these women,
وبينما نجلس مع هؤلاء النساء،
some who have experienced violence and some who have not survived them,
اللواتي اختبر بعضهن العنف والبعض لم ينجو منهن،
we have an opportunity
لدينا فرصة
to reverse what happened at the beginning of this talk,
لعكس ما حدث فى بداية هذه المحادثة،
when we could not stand for these women
عندما لم نستطع الوقوف لهؤلاء النساء
because we did not know their names.
لأننا لم نعرف أسماءهن.
So at the end of this clip, there's going to be a roll call.
لذا في نهاية هذا الفيديو سيكون هناك نداء للأسماء.
Several black women's names will come up.
سوف يعرض العديد من أسماء النساء السود.
I'd like those of you who are able to join us in saying these names
أود من الذين لديهم القدرة على الانضمام إلينا ترديد هذه الأسماء
as loud as you can,
بأعلى ما يمكنهم،
randomly, disorderly.
عشوائيًا، دون انتظام.
Let's create a cacophony of sound
دعونا نصطنع جلبة صوتية
to represent our intention
لنوضح عزمنا
to hold these women up,
على رفع هؤلاء النساء عاليًا،
to sit with them,
لنجلس معهن،
to bear witness to them,
لنشهد لهن،
to bring them into the light.
لنُسلط عليهن الأضواء.
(Singing) Abby Dobson: Say,
"غناء" (آبي دوبسون): انطق،
say her name.
انطق اسمها.
Say,
انطق،
(Audience) Shelly!
"الحضور" (شيلى)!
(Audience) Kayla!
"الحضور" (كايلا)!
AD: Oh,
(آبى): اووو،
say her name.
انطق اسمها.
(Audience shouting names)
(الحضور يطلقون الأسماء)
Say, say,
انطق انطق،
say her name.
انطق اسمها.
For all the names
من أجل جميع الأسماء
I'll never know,
التى لم أعرفها
say her name.
انطق اسمها.
KC: Aiyanna Stanley Jones, Janisha Fonville,
(إيانا ستانلي جونز)، (جانيشا فونفيل)،
Kathryn Johnston, Kayla Moore,
(كاثرين جونستون)، (كايلا مور)،
Michelle Cusseaux, Rekia Boyd,
(ميشيل كوسياكس)، (راقيه بويد)،
Shelly Frey, Tarika, Yvette Smith.
(شيلي فراي)، (تاريكا)، (ايفيت سميث).
AD: Say her name.
انطق اسمها.
KC: So I said at the beginning,
كيمبرلا كرينشو: قلت فى البداية،
if we can't see a problem,
إذا لم نستطع أن نرى المشكلة،
we can't fix a problem.
لن نستطيع حلها.
Together, we've come together to bear witness
معًا، أتينا معًا لنشهد
to these women's lost lives.
أن هؤلاء النساء فقدن حياتهن.
But the time now is to move
لكن يجب أن يتغير الوقت الآن
from mourning and grief
من الحزن والكآبة
to action and transformation.
إلى العمل والتحول.
This is something that we can do.
هذا شيء يُمكننا فعله.
It's up to us.
فالأمر عائد إلينا.
Thank you for joining us.
شكرًا لانضمامكم إلينا.
Thank you.
شكرًا لكم.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)